Kenneth W. Newman Records WLU.Coll.0280
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Kenneth W. Newman Records
Inclusive 1971-2004
Washington and Lee University, James G. Leyburn Library Special Collections and Archives
Newman, Kenneth W.
WLU.Coll.0280
1.75 Linear Feet
Biographical / Historical
Newman was a member of the Washington and Lee University Class of 1971. At the time of his retirement after 31 years of federal government service, he held a high-ranking position with the U. S. Postal Inspection Service.
Scope and Contents
Collection includes information on all aspects of criminal activities handled by the U. S. Postal Inspection Service (including mail fraud, drug trafficking, bombs, child pornography, and identity theft) as well as criminal cases undertaken by the Inspection Service for other government agencies, particularly the Department of Justice. Some examples of these cases are the Robert Hanssen spy case, the Ruby Ridge and Waco cases, and the anthrax crisis of 2001.
Anthrax; Postal inspectors; Government, Resistance to; Idaho; Mail fraud; Hanssen, Robert; United States Postal Service. Postal Inspection Service; United States. Department of Justice
- Inspection Service Bulletins, 1971-01-2002-10; United States Postal Service; United States Postal Service. Postal Inspection Service; 82 Item (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Digestion of Activities, Annual Reports, Performance Reports, Strategic Plans, 1973-2004; United States Postal Service. Postal Inspection Service; 28 Item (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Pamphlets
- Annual Reports, 1973-2004; United States Postal Service. Postal Inspection Service; 13 Item (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Report of the Commission on a Safe and Secure Workplace - USPS, 2000-08; United States Postal Service; 1 Item (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Report of FBI Security Programs - Hanssen Spy Case, 2002-03; United States Postal Service. Postal Inspection Service; 1 Item (Box 1, Folder 6)
  United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation; Hanssen, Robert
- Financial Crimes Task Force of Western Pennsylvania - Website, FBI Bulletin Article, DVD, 1995-01-2005-01; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation; 3 Item (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Investigation of the Lexington 1992 Incidents at Ruby Ridge, Idaho, 1992-1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation
- Investigation of the April 1993 Incidents at Waco, Texas, 1993-2000; Danforth, John C. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Eric-Way Mail Fraud Case - Reports, Newspaper Articles, IS Bulletin, 1979-1980; 7 Item (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Scope and Contents
  Kenneth Newman acted as an investigator on the Eric-Way fraud case.
  United States Postal Service. Postal Inspection Service; Newman, Kenneth W.
- Miscellaneous General Inspection Services and Crime Prevention Brochures, 1982-2003; United States Postal Service. Postal Inspection Service; United States Postal Service; 22 Item (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mail Order/Rebate/Identity Theft Brochures, 1998-2001; United States Postal Service; 6 Item (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Brochures
- Forensics: Georgetown and ASCLD Certificates, Handwriting Identification Article, Handwriting Demonstration Chat and Typewriter Examination Templates, 1975-1986; American Society of Crime Laboratory Directors; Georgetown University; 4 Item (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Mail Center Security, 2002; United States Postal Service; United States. Department of Justice; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation; 5 Item (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Operation Avalanche, 1999-2001; 5 Item (Box 2, Folder 15)
  This file consists of information about 'Operation Avalanche,' an investigation of the largest known commercial child pornography business.
  Child pornography -- Law and legislation -- U.S. states; Newman, Kenneth W.; Nolan, John M.; United States Postal Service. Postal Inspection Service
- National Institute of Justice Research Reports: Eyewitness Evidence and Electronic Crime Scene Evidence, 1999; 2001; United States. Department of Justice; 2 Item (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Photographs (Press Conferences, with Attorney Generals, Miscellaneous), 1981-2002; 10 Item (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Photographs; Newman, Kenneth W.; Potter, John E.; Thornburgh, Dick; Reno, Janet; Freeh, Louis J.; Barr, William P.; Bolger, W. F.; United States Postal Service. Postal Inspection Service; Federal Express Corporation
- Commendations, Awards, and Certificates, 1971-2002; Fisher, D. Michael; Fuqua School of Business (Duke University); Pennsylvania Chiefs of Police Association; United States Postal Service. Postal Inspection Service; 14 Item (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Awards; Letters; Newman, Kenneth W.; Nolan, John M.; Potter, John E.; Weaver, Kenneth
- Resume, IS Career, Retirement, Post-Retirement, 1971-2005; American University (Washington, D.C.); 14 Item (Box 2, Folder 19)
  This file also includes photographs from Postal Inspection Graduating Class of 1972.
  Letters; Newman, Kenneth W.
- Crisis Management - Anthrax Classroom Presentation, 2001-2005; Newman, Kenneth W.; United States Postal Service. Postal Inspection Service; 24 Item (Box 2, Folder 20)
  This file includes presentations, articles, and U.S. Postal Inspection Services communication plans.
- Drugs in the Mail - Congressional Testimony, 2001; Newman, Kenneth W.; 2 Item (Box 2, Folder 21)
  This file consists of Kenneth Newman's writen testimony reporting to Chairman Mica on the inspection of drugs in the mail.
  Mica, John
- "Case: U.S. Postal Service and Workplace Violence", 1 Item (Box 2, Folder 22)
  This file consists of an article about violent incidents in the U.S. Postal Service workplace, such as: 'Edmond' and 'The Royal Oak Incident.'
  United States Postal Service
- Book - "Ruby Ridge - The Truth and Tragedy of the Randy Weaver Family" by Jess Walter, 2002; Walter, Jess; 1 Item (Box 3)
  Books
- Book - "From Freedom to Slaver" by Gerry Spence, 1995; Spence, Gerry; 1 Item (Box 3)
  Books; Weaver family
- Three Feature Length Motion Pictures: "Appointment with Danger," "The Inspectors," and "The Inspectors 2", 1998; 2001; 1949; Gossett, Louis, Jr.; Silverman, Jonathan; 3 Item (Box 3)
  'Appointment with Danger,' 1949 - VHS'The Inspectors,' 1998 - VHS'The Inspectors 2,' 2001 - DVD
  DVDs
- DVD - Drug Trafficking in the Mail Congressional Testimony, 1985-2001; Newman, Kenneth W.; 1 Item (Box 3)
  This file also includes 'Forensic adn Technical Services Branch,' 1985, 'Robbery of Carrier - Memphis,' 1990, 'Antrhax Press Conference,' 2001, 'Pauchueanu Prison - USPMO Scheme,' 1992, '900 Pone Scheme - Memphis,' 1990, and 'USPS Employee Drug Arrests - Nashville,' 1991.
- Delivering Justice DVDs, 2004; United States Postal Service. Postal Inspection Service; 2 Item (Box 3)
  This file includes 'Delivering Justice - Work@Home Scams: They Just Don't Pay!' and 'Delivering Justice - Dialing for Justice.'
- Crime Prevention Commemorative U.S. Postage Stamp Folder, 1984-09-26; United States Postal Service; 1 Item (Box 3)
  This file consists of a folder with booklets and information the commemorative stamp, as well as a sheet of stamps.
  Postage stamps; Crime prevention
- "9/11 and Anthrax: My Story" and Investigation Bulletins, 2005-2009; Newman, Kenneth W.; United States Postal Service. Postal Inspection Service; 5 Item The items are contained by a red folder (Box 3)
  Anthrax -- Law and legislation